# Victory Onuoha

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 

VictoryOnuoha@cmail.carleton.ca 613-608-9686 linkedin.com/in/victoryrita-onuoha github.com/VictoryOnuoha Ottawa, Canada

#### **PROFILE**

Proven Full Stack Developer with a previous background in Neuroscience and 1+ years of experience in software development.

I decided to embark on a career transition because I wanted a role that encouraged growth and had an impact on the global community.

I am passionate about user experience and producing accessible software that is efficient.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, SQL, API's, Axios, NodeJS, Express JS, SQL, Git, Wireframing, Deployment, Debugging, Testing. Relational Databases, Agile Project Management

#### **PROJECTS**

# Full Stack developer | "SprintDay"

JAN 2022 - FEB 2022, BRAINSTATION

- Developed mobile-first react web apps to help over 1,500 users track projects and tasks using React.js on the frontend & Node.js on the backend
- Designed UI Wireframe & database tables for a responsive webapp with Figma, React JS & SQL to enable quick customization for tasks that save users time

# Front End Developer | "BandSite"

JUNE 2022 - JUNE 2022, BRAINSTATION

- Created responsive web apps and optimized site by adding comments feature via an API that can support over 1000+ users
- Enhanced website using Javascript to allow dynamic interaction for concert booking user feature

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Executive Admin Assistant | Appletree Medical Group**

NOV 2020 - PRESENT, CANADA, OTTAWA

- Collaborated with over 30+ team members to act as a resource for new company initiatives to improve operational efficiency by communicating closely with the executive team
- Restructured training documentations using problem solving skills leading to a 45% increase in productivity

## Medical Admin Assistant | Appletree Medical Group

JUL 2019 - NOV 2020, CANADA, OTTAWA

 Resolved inquiries for over 50 third party clients each week using strong communication and analytical skills

# Founding Member | Baddies in Tech

Oct 2020 - Present, CANADA, OTTAWA

- As a BiT Founding Member, I facilitated the creation of a 20 person organization to facilitate diversity in tech by utilizing leadership and problem solving skills to lead the organization
- Lead the 5+ BiT Content team by the creation of content and quizzes using analytical & organizational skills leading to an increase of BiT users by 20% during BiT Website Launch

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BrainStation | Diploma Candidate, Web Development**

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022, CANADA, OTTAWA

## CodeCademy | Online Certificate, Front End Development

JUNE 2021 - 2022, CANADA, OTTAWA

## Carleton University | Bachelors in Science | Neuroscience

SEP 2013 - 2017, CANADA, OTTAWA

• Entrance Scholarship for Academic Excellence